--==本字幕由 新浪微博@纸巾老湿eric 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩字幕 请关注 新浪微博@纸巾老湿eric
（地球，1988年）
（劲爆舞曲大帝国第一集）
彼得
Peter.
你妈有话跟你说
Your momma wants to speak with you.
来，彼得，耳机拿下来
Come on, Pete. Take these fool things off.
怎么又跟别人打架了，宝贝？
Why have you been fighting with the other boys again, baby?
彼得？
Peter?
他们杀死一只无辜的青蛙
They killed a little frog that ain't done nothing.
用棍子把它弄死
Smushed it with a stick.
你个性跟你爸好像
You're so like your daddy.
连长相都一个样
You even look like him.
他就跟天使一样
And he was an angel.
浑身散发纯洁的光芒
- Composed out of pure light. - Mer?
梅儿？
你不是有礼物要给彼得吗？
You got a present there for Peter, don't you?
没错
Of course.
拿去
There.
我帮你收起来，彼得
I've got you covered, Pete.
等我走了你再拆，好吗？
You open it up when I'm gone, okay?
你外公…
Your grandpa...
会好好照顾你的
is gonna take such good care of you.
至少在你爸回来接你之前
At least until your daddy comes back to get you.
拉我的手
Take my hand.
彼得
Peter.
彼得，拉呀
Pete, come on.
拉着我的手
Take my hand.
妈？
Mom?
不…
No! No! No! No!
妈，不！
Mom! No!
跟我来
- Come with me. - No!
不
No!
你得待在这里，拜托
You've got to stay here. Please.
不
No...
好吗？
Okay?
不
No.
妈
Mom!
（26年后）
（莫拉格，废弃行星）
（劲爆舞曲大帝国第一集）
放下武器
Drop it!
嘿
Uh, hey.
马上放下武器 好，老兄别冲动
- Drop it, now! - Hey, cool, man. No problem.
安啦，一切都没问题
No problem at all.
你怎么知道这个？
How do you know about this?
我根本不知道它是什么东东
I don't even know what that is.
我只是捡破烂的
I'm just a junker, man. I was just checking stuff out.
刚好路过进来看看
你不像，你一身破坏者的打扮
You don't look like a junker. You're wearing Ravager garb.
这只是衣服而已
This is just an outfit, man.
忍者龟，最好别再戳我
Ninja Turtle, you better stop poking me.
叫什么名字？
What is your name?
我叫彼得奎尔，大哥别激动
My name is Peter Quill, okay? Dude, chill out.
- 快走   - 为什么？
- Move! - Why?
罗南可能有问题问你
Ronan may have questions for you.
听我说
Hey, you know what?
你可能比较熟悉我另一个绰号
There's another name you might know me by.
星爵
Star-Lord.
啥？
Who?
星爵，大名鼎鼎的传奇恶棍
Star-Lord, man. Legendary outlaw.
没听过？
- Guys? - Move!
快走
当我没说
Ah, forget this.
彼得
Peter?
怎么回事？
What happened?
你是…
Hey, uh...
Uh... I...
贝丽
- Bereet. - Bereet!
老实说，我忘了你在这里
Look, I'm gonna be totally honest with you. I forgot you're here.
克里帝国各地今天发生暴动
Scattered riots broke out
across the Kree Empire today
抗议克里王与柴达星的新星至尊
protesting the recent peace treaty signed by the Kree Emperor
最近签的和平协定
and Xandar's Nova Prime.
彼得，有你电话
Peter, you have call.
- 等等，不要接   - 奎尔？
- No, wait, don't! - Quill?
勇度
Hey, Yondu.
我在莫拉格星
I'm here on Morag.
你和宇宙灵球都不在这里
Ain't no Orb, ain't no you.
我在附近，想帮你省点事
Well, I was in the neighborhood. I thought I'd save you the hassle.
你现在在哪里？
Well, where are you at now, boy?
金拍谢
I feel really bad about this, but I'm not gonna tell you that.
我不告诉你
我做牛做马才把这件事搞定
- I slaved putting this deal together. - Slaved?
打几通电话叫做牛做马？
Making a few calls is "slaved"? I mean, really?
And now you're gonna rip me off!
不能这样，我们破坏者有行规的
We do not do that to each other. We're Ravagers. We got a code.
对，行规就是"不拿白不拿"
Yeah, and that code is "steal from everybody."
- 我去地球接你时…   - 接我
When I picked you up on Terra...
"Picked me up."
- 我的伙伴还想吃你咧   -是吗？
these boys of mine wanted to eat you.
他们以前没尝过地球人的味道
Yeah?
They ain't never tasted any Terran before.
是我阻止他们
I stopped them. You're alive because of me!
你是因为我才有这条小命
我会找到你，一定会
I Will find you, I Will...
Put a bounty on him!
悬赏奖金逮捕他
四万块，我要活捉他
Forty K.
- But I want him back alive. - Yeah, Cap.
- 是，队长   - 活捉？
- Alive? - That's what I said.
没错
当初你去接他
I told you when you picked that kid up,
我就说应该把他送走
you should have delivered him like we was hired to do!
他只是货物
He was cargo!
你老是对他这么心软
You have always been soft on him.
我只有对你才心软
You're the only one I'm being soft on!
不必担心奎尔先生
Now, don't you worry about Mr. Quill.
只要把他捉回来
As soon as we get him back here,
我就亲手杀了他
I'm gonna kill him myself.
我们要担心的是
What we do need to worry about,
还有谁想要这颗球
is who else out there wants that Orb!
（暗星号，克里帝国战舰）
他们称呼我恐怖份子
They call me "terrorist,"
激进份子，狂人
"radical," "zealot,"
因为我遵照克里人的古老法律
because I obey the ancient laws of my people, the Kree,
惩罚违法者
and punish those who do not.
因为我不原谅你们
Because I do not forgive your people
杀死我父亲
for taking the life of my father,
还有我祖父，我曾祖父
and his father, and his father before him.
我们之间的千年战争
A thousand years of war between us will not be forgotten!
不可能就此罢休
手下留情啊！
You can't do this! Our government signed a peace treaty.
我们政府签了和平协定
我的政府不知羞耻
My government knows no shame.
你们柴达的人和文化是一种病
You Xandarians and your culture are a disease.
你…
You
永远不会统治柴达
will never rule Xandar.
没错
No.
我会治愈它
I will cure it!
罗南
Ronan,
科拉特回来了
Korath has returned.
主人，他是个贼
Master, he is a thief,
自称星爵的小混混
an outlaw who calls himself Star-Lord.
我们发现他与人达成协议
But we have discovered he has an agreement
要为一个中间人拿到宇宙灵球
to retrieve the Orb for an intermediary known
那个人叫中介者
as The Broker.
我答应替萨诺斯夺回宇宙灵球
I promised Thanos I would retrieve the Orb for him.
那么他才会为我摧毁柴达
Only then will he destroy Xandar for me.
涅布拉，到柴达去帮我拿灵球
Nebula, go to Xandar and get me the Orb.
这是我的荣幸
It will be my honor.
也会是你的死期
It will be your doom.
如果再失败，你拿什么东西
If this happens again, you'll be facing our father
面见我们父亲
without his prize.
我跟你一样
I'm a daughter of Thanos.
是萨诺斯的女儿
Just like you.
但我了解柴达
But I know Xandar.
罗南已经下令我…
Ronan has already decreed that I...
不要替我发言
Do not speak for me.
你不会，也不能失败
You will not fail.
我何曾失败过？
Have I ever?
（柴达，新星帝国首都）
柴达人
Xandarians.
真是一堆鲁蛇
What a bunch of losers.
他们尽干些肤浅的蠢事
All of them in a big hurry to get from something stupid,
真可悲
to nothing at all. Pathetic.
瞧瞧这家伙
Look at this guy!
他的发型伤害我们眼睛
Can you believe they call us criminals,
竟然还叫我们是罪犯
when he's assaulting us with that haircut?
这什么鬼东西？自以为很酷
What is this thing? Look how it thinks it's so cool.
要人牵就不酷了，自己走，小怪咖
It's not cool to get help! Walk by yourself, you little gargoyle.
看看这个糟老头
Look at Mr. Smiles over here.
杯杯，你老婆呢？老色胚
Where's your wife, old man? What a class-A prevert.
Right, Groot?
对不对，格鲁特？
格鲁特
Groot?
别喝喷泉水，北七
Don't drink fountain water, you idiot.
恶毙了
- That's disgusting! - Mmm.
你有喝，我刚刚看到了
Yes, you did. I just saw you doing it.
干嘛撒谎？
Why are you lying?
Whoop.
看来有赏金可拿了
Looks like we got one.
地球人，是谁这么想找到你？
Okay, humie, how bad does someone wanna find you?
（逃亡者：彼得奎尔，要活捉）
四万块？格鲁特，咱们要削翻了
40,000 units? Groot, we're gonna be rich.
- 奎尔先生   - 中介者
- Mr. Quill. - Broker.
宇宙灵球
The Orb.
照你的吩咐
- As commissioned. - Where's Yondu?
勇度呢？
他不能来，要我代为问候
Wanted to be here. Sends his love.
他叫我告诉你
And told me to tell you,
你的眉毛堪称是"今日我最美"
that you got the best eyebrows in the business.
这是什么？
What is it?
我的原则是绝不谈论客户
It's my policy never to discuss my clients, or their needs.
或他们的需求
我为了拿到它差点送掉小命
Yeah, well, I almost died getting it for you.
这是你的职业风险
An occupational hazard, I'm sure, in your line of work.
有个脑袋空固力的怪咖替罗南卖命
Some machine-headed freak, working for a dude named Ronan.
罗南？
Ronan? I'm sorry, Mr. Quill.
抱歉，奎尔先生
真抱歉，如果扯上罗南
I truly am.
But I want no part of this transaction
这笔交易我可不想碰
- if Ronan is involved. - Whoa, whoa, whoa!
罗南是谁？
Who's Ronan?
克里国的疯子，对和平协定很不满
A Kree fanatic, outraged by the peace treaty,
不把我们柴达文化消灭
who will not rest until Xandarian culture, my culture,
他绝不罢休
- is wiped from existence! - Whoa, whoa!
拜托
- Come on. - He's someone
这个人我惹不起
whose bad side I'd rather not be on.
啊我你就惹得起喔？
What? What about my bad side?
再会，奎尔先生
Farewell, Mr. Quill.
我们讲好的，老兄
Hey, we had a deal, bro!
怎么了？
What happened?
这家伙说话不算话
Ah, this guy just backed out of a deal on me.
我最痛恨不讲信用的人
If there's one thing I hate, it's a man without integrity.
彼得奎尔，人称星爵
Peter Quill. People call me Star-Lord.
你像个注重信誉的人
You have the bearing of a man of honor.
我是不敢这么说啦
Well, you know, I wouldn't say that.
其实是大家都这么说啦
People say it about me, all the time,
但我不喜欢老王卖瓜
but it's not something I would ever say about myself.
Ooh!
本来不打算动粗的
This wasn't the plan.
Ah!
盖布袋
Put him in the bag. Put him in the bag!
不
No! Not her, him!
不是她，是他
公的母的傻傻分不清楚喔
Learn genders, man.
Ow!
用咬的？犯规啊
Biting? That's not fair!
别太激动
Take it easy!
Ow!
笨蛋
Fool. You should have learned.
你该学到教训的
我学不会，这是我的毛病
I don't learn. One of my issues.
搞什么鬼
What the...
别笑了，北七，你是职业高手
Quit smiling, you idiot. You're supposed to be a professional.
开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
喂
Ooh. Hey!
本大爷做事喜欢干净俐落
I live for the simple things.
要痛就让你痛到靠北
Like how much this is gonna hurt.
扭个过瘾吧，小子
Yeah. Writhe, little man.
它会长回来的，北七
It'll grow back, you d'ast idiot.
别唉了
Quit whining.
89P13受试者
Subject 89P13, drop your weapon.
放下武器
靠
Aw, crap.
根据新星军团的权力
By the authority of the Nova Corps,
- you are under arrest... - All right. Come on up.
你因危及性命与破坏财产而被捕
for endangerment to life and the destruction of property.
你不是星星王子吗？
Hey! If it isn't Star-Prince.
星爵
- Star-Lord. - Oh, sorry. "Lord."
拍谢，星爵
我逮捕过他偷窃，他有绰号
I picked this guy up a while back for petty theft.
He's got a code name.
Yeah. Stay out of the way.
拜托，那是在江湖走跳的称号
Come on, man. It's a... It's an outlaw name.
放轻松
Just relax, pal.
有绰号没关系，不奇怪
It's cool to have a code name. It's not that weird.
好大的官威啊
Fascists.
罗南摧毁银河各地的柴达基地
Ronan is destroying
Xandarian outposts throughout the galaxy.
（柴达新星军团总部）
这样应该会让克里帝国有点反应
I should think that would call for some slight response on the part of the Kree.
我们签了和平协定，你还要怎样？
We signed your peace treaty, Nova Prime.
What more do you want?
克里帝国至少发表声明
At least a statement from the Kree Empire
谴责他的行动
saying that they condemn his actions.
他在屠杀儿童
He is slaughtering children.
家庭
Families.
那是你家的事
That is your business.
我还有别的事要忙
Now, I have other matters to attend to.
俗辣
Prick.
Well, some good news.
有好消息
我们逮到了罗南的同伙
It looks like we've apprehended one of Ronan's compatriots.
葛摩菈
Gamora.
经过调教训练，简直像人间凶器
Surgically modified and trained as a living weapon.
疯狂泰坦萨诺斯的养女
The adopted daughter of the Mad Titan, Thanos.
最近她和妹妹涅布拉为罗南效力
Recently, Thanos lent her and her sister Nebula out to Ronan,
因此我们认为萨诺斯与罗南合作
which leads us to believe that Thanos and Ronan are working together.
89P13受试者，自称火箭
Subject 89P13. Calls itself "Rocket."
受非法基因与模控实验的低等生物
The result of illegal genetic
and cybernetic experiments
on a lower life form.
搞什么鬼？
What the hell?
他们叫它格鲁特
They call it "Groot."
这个树人最近跟在89P13身边
A humanoid plant that's been travelling recently
当他的室内植物兼保镖
as 89P13's personal houseplant/muscle.
彼得杰森奎尔，来自地球
Peter Jason Quill, from Terra.
由一批称为破坏者的佣兵带大
Raised from youth by a band of mercenaries called the Ravagers,
领袖是勇度
led by Yondu Udonta.
拍谢喔
Oh, I'm sorry.
我不知道这个机器怎么用
I didn't know how this machine worked.
一群天兵
What a bunch of a-holes.
四个都送去奇恩监狱
Transport all four to the Kyln.
（奇恩高度戒备监狱）
大部分新星军团都想好好执法
I guess most of Nova Corps wanna uphold the laws,
但这些人爱贪污又残酷
but these ones here, they're corrupt and cruel.
但那不是我的问题
But, hey, that's not my problem.
我不会待很久
I ain't gonna be here long.
我越狱22次，这只是小菜一碟
I've escaped 22 prisons. This one's no different.
你好狗运，那个美眉出现
You're lucky the broad showed up,
because otherwise, me and Groot
不然我和格鲁特早拿到赏金
would be collecting that bounty right now,
勇度和那些破坏者
and you'd be getting drawn and quartered
就把你五马分尸了
by Yondu and those Ravagers.
这些年来多少人想干掉我
I've had a lot of folks try to kill me over the years.
一棵树和一只浣熊只能靠边站
I ain't about to be brought down by a tree and a talking raccoon.
等一下
Hold.
- 浣熊是什么？   - 浣熊是什么？
- What's a raccoon? - "What's a raccoon?"
就是你，蠢蛋
It's what you are, stupid.
我就是我
Ain't no thing like me, except me.
没人能比
那个宇宙灵球
So, this Orb has a real shiny blue suitcase,
有闪亮的蓝色外壳，宛如魔法宝石
Ark of the Covenant, Maltese Falcon sort of vibe.
- 它是什么？   - 我是格鲁特
- What is it? - I am Groot.
又怎样？那个球是什么？
So what? What's the Orb?
我对无耻鼠辈无话可说
I have no words for an honorless thief.
不过是杀人魔的走狗
Pretty high and mighty coming from the lackey
却如此自命清高
of a genocidal maniac.
对，我知道你是谁
Yeah, I know who you are.
你无人不知无人不晓
Anyone who's anyone knows who you are.
对，我们知道你是谁
Yeah, we know who you are.
她是谁？
- Who is she? - I am Groot.
我是格鲁特
你说过了
Yeah, you said that.
我夺球不是为了罗南
I wasn't retrieving the Orb for Ronan.
我是要背叛他
I was betraying him.
我跟人协议，要将它卖给第三方
I had an agreement to sell it to a third party.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
我听到耳朵要流脓了
Well, that's just as fascinating as the first 89 times you told me that.
这个青仔丛有毛病啊？
What is wrong with Giving Tree, here?
他跟你我一样吐不出什么好话
Well, he don't know talking good like me and you.
所以他懂的字只有我、是、格鲁特
So his vocabulistics is limited to "I" and "am" and "Groot."
顺序还不能变
Exclusively in that order.
很快就会无聊到爆
I tell you what, that's gonna wear real thin, real fast.
喂
Hey.
不要拿
Put that away.
Hey!
喂
蓝脸怪，把拎杯的耳机放下
Listen to me, you big blue bastard. Take those headphones off.
那是我的，是扣押品
That's mine. Those belong to impound.
那录音带和随身听是我的
That tape and that player is mine!
蓝色瑞典人"就爱这感觉"，1973年
Hooked on a Feeling, Blue Swede, 1973.
那首歌是我的
That song belongs to me!
你先，你先
- You first! You first! - Murderer!
我先来找你，葛摩菈，你死定了
Coming for you first, Gamora! You're dead!
你是人渣，你是人渣
You're scum! You're scum!
我说过
It's like I said,
她名声响叮当
she's got a rep.
这里很多囚犯的家人
A lot of prisoners here have lost their families
都被罗南一帮人杀害
to Ronan and his goons.
她顶多撑个一天
She'll last a day, tops.
杀人凶手
Murderer!
警卫会保护她吧？
The guards will protect her, right?
他们是防止我们逃走
They're here to stop us from getting out.
才不管我们在里面自相残杀
They don't care what we do to each other inside.
无论未来有多凄惨
Whatever nightmares the future holds,
跟我的过去相比都不算什么
are dreams compared to what's behind me.
新货到
Check out the new meat.
我要把你全身涂满果酱
I'm gonna slather you up in Gunavian jelly,
然后尽情…
and go to town...
我们把话讲清楚
Let's make something clear.
这家伙是我们的摇钱树
This one here is our booty!
你们想动他一根寒毛
You wanna get to him,
得先过我们这关
You go through us!
讲白一点
Or, more accurately,
我们会解决你
we go through you.
我是他们在罩的喔
I'm with them.
我讨厌你
I hate you.
住哪间牢房都没有用
No cell's gonna protect you for long.
You're dead!
你死定了
死定了
Dead!
带她去淋浴间
Take her down to the showers.
在那里清洗血迹比较方便
It'll be easier to clean up the blood down there.
奎尔，你去哪？
Quill, where you going?
奎尔
Quill.
Quill!
葛摩菈，把这当作你的死刑
Gamora, consider this a death sentence
谁叫你在银河犯下重罪
for your crimes against the galaxy.
你敢？
You dare?
知道我是谁吧？
You know who I am, yes?
你是德克斯
You're Drax.
毁灭者
The Destroyer.
- 奎尔   - 你知道我不是浪得虚名
Quill!
And you know why they call me this.
你杀死罗南几十个手下
You slayed dozens of Ronan's minions.
罗南杀了我太太奥薇特
Ronan murdered my wife, Ovette,
和我女儿卡梅莉
and my daughter, Camaria.
手段凶残冷血
He slaughtered them where they stood.
当时他还狂笑
And he laughed!
奎尔，你在干嘛？
Quill?
她的命
Her life
轮不到你来处置
is not yours to take.
他杀了我家人
He killed my family.
我会以牙还牙
I shall kill one of his in return.
当然，德克斯
Of course, Drax. Here, I...
给你
奎尔，你干嘛？
Quill! What are you doing?
我不是罗南或萨诺斯的家人
I'm no family to Ronan or Thanos.
只有我才能阻止他
I'm your only hope at stopping him.
Ah!
女人，你的话对我毫无意义
Woman, your words mean nothing to me!
别激动
- Hey! Hey, hey, hey! Hey! - Oh, crap.
惨了
如果干掉罗南真是你的终极目标
You know, if killing Ronan is truly your sole purpose,
这样于事无补
I don't think this is the best way to go about it.
你不是这婊子想干掉的家伙吗？
Are you not the man this wench attempted to kill?
想干掉我的女人有一拖拉库
Well, I mean, she's hardly the first woman
to try and do that to me.
这是一个破坏者正妹弄的
Look, this is from a smoking-hot Rajak girl.
不爽我早上不告而别，拿叉子刺我
Stabbed me with a fork.
Didn't like me skipping out on her at sunrise.
这是一个克里马子想捅我胸部
I got, right here, a Kree girl tried to rip out my thorax.
她逮到我跟一个阿斯嘉女生厮混
She caught me with this skinny little A'askavariian
对方在新星军团档案室工作
who worked in Nova Records.
我是想搜集情报
I was trying to get information.
你见过阿斯嘉人吗？
You ever see an A'askavariian?
他们有触角，牙齿像针一样
They have tentacles, and needles for teeth.
你要是以为我对那种人有兴趣…
If you think I'm seriously interested in that, then...
你不在乎
You don't care. But here's the point.
重点是
她背叛罗南，他会回来找她
She betrayed Ronan. He's coming back for her.
一旦他来
And when he does,
你就能…
that's when you...
我干嘛把手指放在他喉咙上？
Why would I put my finger on his throat?
啥小？
What?
不，这是比喻
Oh, no, it's a symbol.
代表你割他喉咙
This is a symbol for you slicing his throat.
我不会割他喉咙
I would not slice his throat.
我会剁掉他的头
I would cut his head clean off.
这是代表杀人的说法
It's a general expression for you killing somebody.
你听过，看过吧？
You've heard of this. You've seen this, right?
- 知道什么意思   - 对
- You know what that is. - Yeah. Yeah.
- 大家都知道   - 不
- Everyone knows. - No, no.
我意思是你让她活命
What I'm saying is, you want to keep her alive.
别当罗南的刽子手
Don't do his work for him.
我喜欢你的刀，我收下
I like your knife. I'm keeping it.
那是人家最喜欢的刀
- That was my favorite knife. - Listen!
听好
我才不鸟你的死活
I could care less whether you live or whether you die.
那何必阻止那个大只佬？
- Then why stop the big guy? - Simple.
很简单
你知道去哪卖我的球
You know where to sell my Orb.
我们都在这里，怎么卖？
How are we gonna sell it when we and it are still here?
我朋友火箭
My friend Rocket, here,
越狱22次
has escaped 22 prisons.
我们会逃出去
Oh, we're getting out.
然后去找勇度领你的赏金
And then we're headed straight to Yondu to retrieve your bounty.
你的买主愿意付多少钱
How much was your buyer willing to pay you for my Orb?
买我的球？
40亿
Four billion units.
- 啥？   - 哇靠
- What? - Holy shit.
那球是我摆脱萨诺斯和罗南的机会
That Orb is my opportunity to get away from Thanos and Ronan.
你们要是让我们逃走
If you free us,
我直接带你们去找买主
I'll lead you to the buyer directly
利润三人均分
and I'll split the profit between the three of us.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
四个人分
Four of us.
有危险就睡
Asleep for the danger, awake for the money,
听到钱就醒，这哪招啊
as per frickin' usual.
你遭到背叛了，罗南
You have been betrayed, Ronan.
我们只知道她被捕
We know only that she has been captured.
葛摩菈可能拿到了宇宙灵球
Gamora may yet recover the Orb.
不，狱中消息说葛摩菈有夺球计划
No! Our sources within the Kyln say Gamora has her own plans for the Orb.
你和萨诺斯的合作关系
Look, your partnership with Thanos
岌岌可危
is at risk.
萨诺斯要求你立刻出面
Thanos requires your presence. Now!
（避难所，萨诺斯领域）
恕我直言，萨诺斯，令嫒闯的祸
With all due respect, Thanos, your daughter made this mess,
你却找我来
and yet you summon me.
劝你说话小心点，控诉者
I would lower my voice, Accuser.
首先她跟几个原始人打输了
First, she lost a battle with some primitive.
萨诺斯让葛摩菈听命于你
Thanos put Gamora under your charge.
然后她被新星军团逮捕
Then she was apprehended by the Nova Corps.
毫无贡献的是你
You are the one here with nothing to show for it.
你的消息来源说她一直背叛我们
Your sources say that she meant to betray us the whole time!
讲话客气点
Lower your tone!
虽然我是你的…
I may be your...
我只要求你认真看待这件事
I only ask that you take this matter seriously.
我唯一不认真看待的
The only matter I do not take seriously, boy,
就是你
is you.
你的政治算计太无聊
Your politics bore me.
行径跟小孩一样幼稚
Your demeanor is that of a pouty child.
显然
And, apparently, you alienated my favorite daughter, Gamora.
你又离间我最疼爱的女儿葛摩菈
我会遵守我们的协议，克里人
I shall honor our agreement, Kree,
只要你拿宇宙灵球来给我
if you bring me the Orb.
要是再两手空空来见我
But return to me again empty-handed,
我会让你血流成河
and I will bathe the starways in your blood.
谢谢老爸，听起来很公平
Thanks, Dad. Sounds fair.
这场仗你打不赢的
This is one fight you won't win.
我们到奇恩去
Let's head to the Kyln.
想逃走就得进入那座了望台
If we're gonna get out of here,
we're gonna need to get into that watchtower.
所以需要几样东西
And to do that, I'm gonna need a few things.
警卫都戴着保全臂章
The guards wear security bands
控制人员进出，我需要一个
to control their ins and outs. I need one.
交给我
Leave it to me.
那边那家伙，我要他的义肢
That dude, there. I need his prosthetic leg.
- 他的腿？   - 对
- His leg? - Yeah.
其他部位不用了，瞧他那逊样
God knows I don't need the rest of him. Look at him, he's useless.
好
All right.
最后，后面墙上有块黑色板子
And finally, on the wall back there is a black panel. Blinky yellow light.
闪黄灯那里
看到没？
- Do you see it? - Yeah.
有
后面有夸尼电池，紫箱子绿色电线
There's a quarnyx battery behind it. Purplish box, green wires.
想进了望台，缺它不可
To get into that watchtower, I definitely need it.
要怎么弄到手？
How are we supposed to do that?
这些猪头应该会煞到你
Well, supposably, these bald-bodies find you attractive.
或许你能想想办法
So, maybe you can work out some sort of trade.
开什么玩笑
You must be joking.
不，听说他们觉得你很正
No, I really heard they find you attractive.
那里高达20尺
Look, it's 20 feet up in the air,
又是监狱戒备最森严的地方
and it's in the middle of the most heavily-guarded part of the prison.
上去包准会被发现
It's impossible to get up there without being seen.
我提出计划，需要用到夸尼电池
I got one plan,
and that plan requires a frickin' quarnyx battery,
自己想办法
so figure it out!
Oh!
我能继续讲吗？谢谢
Can I get back to it? Thanks.
这一点很重要
Now, this is important.
电池一被移走，监狱进入紧急模式
Once the battery is removed,
everything is gonna slam into emergency mode.
拿到手之后动作要快
Once we have it, we gotta move quickly,
所以电池一定要最后拿
so you definitely need to get that last.
或者先拿再想办法
Or we could just get it first and improvise.
- 我去弄臂章   - 我弄那只腿
- I'll get the armband. - Leg.
囚犯
Prisoner,
立刻放下装备，回到牢房
drop the device immediately and retreat to your cell,
否则我们就开火
or we will open fire.
我是…
I am
格鲁特
Groot!
开火
Fire!
全体囚犯回到就寝区
All prisoners return to your sleeping areas.
你北七喔！
You idiot!
我没武器怎么跟他们打？
How am I supposed to fight these things without my stuff?
控制住这只禽兽了
The animal is in control.
听我命令开火
Fire on my command!
恐怖小野兽
Creepy little beast!
爽啦
Oh, yeah.
你需要我的什么？
You need my what?
- 我需要这个   - 祝你好运
- I'll need this. - Good luck.
它有线路接到体内
It's internally wired.
我会想办法
I'll figure something out.
把腿放下
Drop the leg!
Drop the leg and move back to your cell!
退回牢房
火箭
Rocket!
往了望台移动
Move to the watchtower!
你
You!
跟阿斯嘉人嘿咻过的哪个
Man who has lain with an A'askavariian!
只有那一次
It was one time, man.
全体警卫全副武装
We need all available guards in full combat gear...
Whoa!
别盯着我瞧，查某人
Spare me your foul gaze, woman.
这家伙怎么在这里？
Why is this one here?
我们答应让他在杀你老板前跟着你
We promised him he could stay by your side until he kills your boss.
我一向说话算话
I always keep my promises,
尤其对方是会杀死我的疯狂大只佬
when they're to muscle-bound whack-jobs
who will kill me if I don't. Here you go.
拿去
假腿是开玩笑的，我只需要这两样
Oh, I was just kidding about the leg.
I just need these two things.
- 啥？   - 我觉得很幽默
- What? - No, I thought it'd be funny.
好笑吗？
Was it funny?
现在他用跳的吗？
Oh, wait, what did he look like hopping around?
我还转帐3万块给他耶
I had to transfer him 30,000 units!
我们要怎么离开？
How are we going to leave?
他有计划
Well, he's got a plan.
对吧？还是你又瞎掰？
Right? Or is that another thing you made up?
我有计划…
I have a plan! I have a plan!
停止你的哀怨
Cease your yammering
带领我们离开这令人恼恨之地
and relieve us from this irksome confinement.
我同意假掰先生的意见
Yeah, I'll have to agree with the walking thesaurus
有道理
on that one.
千万别叫我假掰先生
Do not ever call me a thesaurus.
只是比喻
It's just a metaphor, dude.
他们族人头脑简单
His people are completely literal. Metaphors are gonna go over his head.
比喻左耳进右耳出
我两耳之间畅通无阻
Nothing goes over my head.
很容易进水
My reflexes are too fast. I would catch it.
我死时身边都会是银河脑残王
I'm gonna die surrounded by the biggest idiots in the galaxy.
好大枝的枪
Those are some big guns.
听我口令
On my command!
一号
Number one!
啮齿哥，我们准备执行你的计划
Rodent, we are ready for your plan.
等一下
Hold on!
二号
Number two!
我认得这种动物
I recognize this animal.
小时候我们会烤来吃
We'd roast them over a flame pit as children.
肉质软嫩不柴
Their flesh was quite delicious.
不要喇低赛
Not helping!
三号
Number three!
全体开火
All fire on my command!
听我口令
三
Three!
二
Two!
一
One!
他关闭了人造引力
He turned off the artificial gravity,
只有这里例外
everywhere but in here.
我就说我有计划
I told you I had a plan.
好屌的计划
That was a pretty good plan.
Huh?
在那里，去开我的船
Yeah! There it is. Get my ship.
米兰号，角落蓝橘色那艘
It's the Milano, the orange and blue one over in the corner.
他们害我裤子皱得像酸菜
They crumpled my pants up into a ball.
真没礼貌，他们却帮你摺裤子
That's rude! They folded yours.
宇宙灵球在那里，走吧
The Orb's there. Let's go.
等一下
- Wait, wait, wait. - What?
- 怎样？   - 那混帐没放回来
That bastard didn't put it back.
- 放什么回来？   - 拿着
- Put what back? - Here.
带他们上船，我马上过去
Get them to the ship. I will be right back.
- 你要怎么…   - 别让米兰号跑远
- How are you gonna possibly... - Just keep the Milano close by.
快去
Go.
去啊
Go!
我的脖子
Ah, my neck!
他要怎么来找我们？
Well, how's he gonna get to us?
他不肯告诉我
He declined to share that information with me.
去他的
Well, screw this, then!
我不想等一个不要命的地球人
I ain't waiting around for some humie with a death wish.
你拿到宇宙灵球了吧？
You got the Orb, right?
对
Yes.
现在不走，我们会被炸成肉酱
If we don't leave now, we will be blown to bits.
不
No!
没有宇宙灵球不能走
We're not leaving without the Orb.
你们看
Behold.
就是要这种气魄
This one shows spirit.
他会是对抗罗南的好伙伴
He shall make a keen ally in the battle against Ronan.
同伴，你去拿什么？
Companion, what were you retrieving?
有够低能
You're an imbecile.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
熊宝贝，你在干嘛？
Yo, Ranger Rick! What are you doing?
怎么问都不问就拆我的船？
You can't take apart my ship without asking me!
- 这什么？   - 不要碰
- See, what is this? - Don't touch that!
- 是炸弹   - 炸弹？
It's a bomb.
- A bomb? - Yup.
你放着它不管？
And you leave it lying around?
我本来要放在箱子里
I was gonna put it in a box.
放箱子能干嘛？
What's a box gonna do?
这个呢？
- How about this one? - No! Whoa. Hey!
别拿
- 不要拿   - 这什么？
- Leave it alone. - Why? What is it?
- 少啰唆   - 嘿
- Shut up. - Hey!
那是什么？
What is that?
以防情况失控
That's for if things get really hardcore.
或是你想炸掉卫星
Or if you wanna blow up moons.
没有人会炸掉卫星
No one's blowing up moons.
你实在很没幽默感
You just wanna suck the joy out of everything.
我需要买主的座标
So, listen, I'm gonna need your buyer's coordinates.
这个方向没错
We're heading in the right direction. For now.
目前没错
想合作，你最好信任我
If we're gonna work together, you might try trusting me a little bit.
你有多信任我？
And how much do you trust me?
告诉我这是什么，我会更信任你
I'd trust you a lot more if you told me what this was.
因为我猜
Because I'm guessing it's some kind of weapon.
它是某种武器
我不知道它是什么
I don't know what it is.
如果是武器，应该用来对付罗南
If it's a weapon, we should use it against Ronan.
放下，笨蛋，你会害死我们
Put it down, you fool. You'll destroy us all.
或只害死你，杀人凶手
Or just you, murderess!
我放过你一条生路，金刚芭比
I let you live once, princess!
我不是金刚芭比
- I am not a princess! - Hey!
在我船上谁都不准杀人
Nobody is killing anybody on my ship!
拿到钱之前我们是命运共同体
We're stuck together until we get the money.
我对钱没兴趣
I have no interest in money.
太好了
Great.
那我们三个可以多分点
That means more money for the three of us.
Mmm?
我们四个
For the four of us.
伙伴
Partners.
我们是有协议
We have an agreement,
但我绝不跟你这种人当伙伴
but I would never be partners with the likes of you.
我会告诉买主我们快到了
I'll tell the buyer we're on our way.
奎尔，你的船脏死了
And Quill, your ship is filthy.
她真是不懂得欣赏
Oh, she has no idea.
若有紫外线灯，这里就像抽象画
If I had a black light,
the place would look like a Jackson Pollock painting.
你有毛病耶，奎尔
You got issues, Quill.
我发誓我不知道他们去哪
I swear. I don't know where they went! I swear.
他如果知道，早就告诉我们
If he knew where they were headed,
he would have already told us.
对
Yeah.
罗南
Ronan,
新星军团派出舰队要捍卫监狱
the Nova Corps sent a fleet to defend the prison.
那么
Well, then,
派死灵号到各处巡逻
send Necrocraft to every corner of the quadrant.
找到宇宙灵球，不计代价
Find the Orb. Any means, any price.
这个地方呢？
And this place?
不能让新星军团知道我们在追什么
The Nova can't know what we're after.
彻底摧毁
Cleanse it!
你还有这样的可爱小玩意吗？
Do you got any other cute little buggers like this one?
我想在控制台上贴一排
I like to stick 'em all in a row on my control console.
我分不出你是不是开玩笑
I can't tell if you're joking or not.
他非常认真
He's being fully serious.
这样的话
In that case, I can show you...
我拿给你看
但先告诉我宇宙灵球是什么
But first, you gonna tell me what this Orb is,
为什么大家这么在乎它
and why everybody cares so damn much about it.
然后再告诉我
And then you gonna tell me,
可能有谁想买
who out there might wanna buy it.
先生，顶级收藏界是…
Sir, the high-end community is a...
顶级收藏界是…
The high-end community is a...
是一个关系紧密…
It's a tight-knit...
关系紧密…
Tight-knit...
顶级收藏界关系非常紧密
The high-end community is a very tight-knit...
我不可能泄漏
I cannot possibly betray
买主的机密
the confidentiality of my buyers!
你的买主到底是谁？
Now, who again is this buyer of yours?
卡琳娜
Carina.
是，主人
Yes, Master.
你们有手肘，对不对？
Your people do have elbows, do they not?
有，主人
We do, Master.
那就好好利用
Then use them.
我不必提醒你
I don't have to remind you
上一个侍从让我失望的下场
what happened to the last attendant who disappointed me.
是吧？
Do I?
动作快，客人快到了
Chop, chop. Our guests will be here soon.
注意，我们快到了
Heads up! We're inbound.
哇塞
Whoa.
那是什么？
What is it?
它叫"知无领域"
It's called Knowhere.
一种宇宙古生物的头颅
The severed head of an ancient celestial being.
当心点，啮齿哥
Be wary headed in, rodent.
这里没有王法可言
There are no regulations whatsoever here.
（无空间，采矿殖民地）
几百年前，帝凡集团派工人来
Hundreds of years ago, the Tivan Group sent workers in
开采头颅内的有机物质
to mine the organic matter within the skull.
骨骼、脑组织、脊髓液
Bone, brain tissue, spinal fluid.
都是稀有资源，在黑市价值很高
All rare resources, highly valued in black markets across the galaxy.
这种危险的非法工作只适合罪犯
It's dangerous and illegal work, suitable only for outlaws.
我来自恶棍星球
Well, I come from a planet of outlaws.
开膛手杰克
Billy the Kid,
宾拉登，陈进星
Bonnie and Clyde, John Stamos.
那地方听起来让我很想去
It sounds like a place, which I would like to visit.
你该去看看
Yeah, you should.
Excuse me.
- 小心你们的皮夹   - 赏点钱吧
- Watch your wallets. - Can you spare any units?
闪边
Get out of here.
你的买主在里面？
Your buyer's in there?
我们在这里等他的代表
We are to wait here for his representative.
滚开
Get out of here!
这样真不尊重人
This is no respectable establishment.
我们等的时候能干嘛？
What do you expect us to do while we wait?
加油…
Yes! Yes!
Whoa!
Yahoo!
我的奥龙尼跟我一样
My Orloni has won,
战无不胜
as I won at all things!
继续把这种液体灌入我们体内
Now, let's put more of this liquid into our bodies.
你第一次说出人话
That's the first thing you said that wasn't bat-shit crazy!
你不知道这里的燃料有多贵
Man, you wouldn't believe what they charge for fuel out here.
这差事我搞不好会赔本
I might actually lose money on this job.
我的客户要我们等
My connection is making us wait.
这只是谈判策略，刚好是我的专长
It's just a negotiation tactic. Trust me, this is my specialty.
你比较擅长…打打杀杀
Where yours is more,
"Stab, stab. Those are my terms."
这是我用的术语
我父亲没特别传授外交手腕
My father didn't stress diplomacy.
萨诺斯？
Thanos?
他不是我父亲
He's not my father.
萨诺斯侵略我家乡时
When Thanos took my home world,
在我眼前杀死我父母
he killed my parents in front of me.
他折磨我
He tortured me,
将我训练成他的武器
turned me into a weapon.
当他说他要为罗南摧毁整个星球
When he said he was going to destroy an entire planet for Ronan,
我无法坐视不管…
I couldn't stand by and...
你为何要为这个冒生命危险？
Why would you risk your life for this?
这是我妈送我的
My mother gave it to me.
她爱跟我分享年轻时喜爱的流行歌
My mom liked sharing with me all the pop songs that she loved growing up.
我刚好在听…
I happened to have it on me,
当我…
when I was...
那天她…
The day that she...
我离开地球那天
You know, when I left Earth.
这要怎么处理？
What do you do with it?
处理？不用，直接听
Do? Nothing. You listen to it. Or you can dance.
也可以跳舞
我是战士兼刺客，不跳舞
I'm a warrior and an assassin. I do not dance.
真的吗？
Really?
地球上有一则关于你这种人的传奇
On my planet, there's a legend about people like you.
它叫…
It's called
"浑身是劲"
Footloose.
里面有个大英雄
And in it, a great hero
叫凯文贝肯
named Kevin Bacon,
他教整座城市的人顶住屁股
teaches an entire city full of people with sticks up their butts that dancing, well...
跳那种舞
超赞的
It's the greatest thing there is.
谁顶住屁股？
Who put the sticks up their butts?
不，那只是…
What? No, that's just a...
- 好残忍   - 只是个说法
- That is cruel. - It's just a phrase
大家常说的
people use.
旋律很轻快
The melody is pleasant!
- 不   - 干嘛啦？
- No! - Ow! What the hell?
我知道你是谁，彼得奎尔
I know who you are, Peter Quill!
我不是无知少女，会被你的…
And I am not some starry-eyed waif here to succumb to your...
把妹招数欺骗
Your pelvic sorcery!
根本不是那么回事
That is not what is happening here.
不，不
Oh, no.
别打了
Stop it!
你想干嘛？
Whoa, whoa, what are you doing?
这只有害动物
This vermin speaks of affairs he knows nothing about!
只会鬼扯乱讲话
没错
- That is true! - He has no respect!
他一点也不尊重人
这也没错
- That is also true! - Hold on! Hold on!
等一下
再叫我有害动物啊，大只佬
Keep calling me vermin, tough guy!
你只想跟别人一样嘲笑我
You just wanna laugh at me like everyone else!
火箭，你醉了，没人在笑你
Rocket, you're drunk. All right? No one's laughing at you.
他觉得我是蠢蛋
He thinks I'm some stupid thing! He does!
大爷我也是千百个不愿意
Well, I didn't ask to get made!
我不愿意被拆解
I didn't ask to be torn apart,
然后一次又一次组合起来
and put back together, over and over
变成一种…
and turned into some...
一种小怪物
Some little monster!
火箭，没人说你是怪物
Rocket, no one's calling you a monster.
他叫我有害动物
He called me "vermin"!
她叫我啮齿哥
She called me "rodent"!
在你脸上轰个五六枪
Let's see if you can laugh
看你还笑不笑得出来
after five or six good shots to your frickin' face!
不…
No, no, no, no!
四十亿耶，火箭
Four billion units! Rocket!
唛安捏
Come on, man. Hey!
再忍耐一个晚上
Suck it up for one more lousy night
你就要削爆了
and you're rich.
好
Fine.
我不能保证这件事结束
But I can't promise, when all this is over
我不会把你们每个猪头都干掉
I'm not gonna kill every last one of you jerks.
看吧，难怪你们都没有朋友
See? That's exactly why none of you have any friends!
刚认识别人就想杀死他们
Five seconds after you meet somebody, you're already trying to kill them!
我们绕了…
We have travelled, halfway across the quadrant.
大半个银河
罗南还活得好好的
And Ronan is no closer to being dead.
- 德克斯   - 让他走
- Drax! - Let him go.
我们不需要他
We don't need him.
葛摩菈小姐
Milady Gamora.
我替主人来接你
I'm here to fetch you for my master.
这一点也不恐怖
Okay, this isn't creepy at all.
我们收藏了银河中
We house the galaxy's largest collection
最多的动物、遗骸，所有物种
of fauna, relics, and species of all manner.
请欢迎
I present to you,
收藏者，坦利亚帝凡
Taneleer Tivan, The Collector.
Oh, my dear Gamora.
我亲爱的葛摩菈
亲眼见到你
How wonderful to meet in the flesh.
真是高兴
少假掰了，帝凡
Let's bypass the formalities, Tivan.
你要的东西在我们手上
We have what we discussed.
那边那个东西…
What is that thing there?
是什么？
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
没想到我会见到格鲁特
I never thought I'd meet a Groot.
先生
Sir...
请让我付钱，我想收藏你的尸骸
You must allow me to pay you now so that I may own your carcass.
当然是等你挂点
At the moment of your death, of course.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
为什么？
Why, so he could turn you into a frickin' chair?
让他把你变成一张椅子吗？
那是你的宠物？
That's your pet?
他的什么？
- His what? - Tivan.
帝凡
我们跑了大半个银河去偷这颗球
We have been halfway around the galaxy, retrieving this Orb.
非常好
Very well, then.
我们看看你带了什么来
Let us see what you brought.
三个夸尼电池，七箱科塔提种子
Three quarnyx batteries, seven cases of Cotati seeds.
很多箱，上次你送给我…
No, cases. Last time, you sent me...
Uh...
你帮我传一个讯息
You shall send a message for me.
我的新朋友
Oh, my new friends.
在开天辟地之前
Before creation itself,
出现六种变异体
there were six singularities.
接着宇宙爆炸成形
Then the universe exploded into existence,
这些系统的残骸
and the remnants of these systems
融成浓缩硬块
were forged into concentrated ingots.
也就是无限宝石
Infinity Stones.
这些宝石
These stones, it seems,
只有具超强力量的个体
can only be brandished
才能驾驭
by beings of extraordinary strength.
请看
Observe.
这些人能用宝石摧毁整个文明
These carriers can use the Stone to mow down entire civilizations
势如破竹
like wheat in a field.
我锉到漏尿了
There's a little pee coming out of me right now.
曾有一段时间
Once, for a moment,
某个团体能共同负荷并操控能量
a group was able to share the energy amongst themselves,
但连他们都很快遭宝石歼灭
but even they were quickly destroyed by it.
美丽耀眼
Beautiful.
无与伦比
Beyond compare.
废话连篇
Blah, blah, blah.
了不起，白毛老爹，但我们想拿钱
We're all very fascinated, whitey. But we'd like to get paid.
该怎么付钱给你们？
How would you like to get paid?
你说呢，姥姥？付现啊
What do you think, fancy man? Units!
没问题
Very well, then.
卡琳娜
Carina.
后退
Stand back.
我再也不是你的奴隶了
I will no longer be your slave!
不
No!
搞什么飞机？
What the...
我竟然以为帝凡能控制球里的东西
How could I think Tivan could contain whatever was within the Orb?
你还拿着它干嘛？
What do you still have it for?
怎么办，丢在里面吗？
What are we gonna do, leave it in there?
你竟然把它放在皮包里
I can't believe you had that in your purse!
这不是皮包，是背包
It's not a purse, it's a knapsack!
我们得拿去给新星军团
We have to bring this to the Nova Corps.
他们或许能控制它
There's a chance they can contain it.
开什么玩笑？
Are you kidding me?
新星军团正通缉我们，交给罗南啦
We're wanted by the Nova Corps. Just give it to Ronan!
好让他摧毁银河吗？
So he can destroy the galaxy?
你怎么突然变大圣人了？
What are you, some saint all of a sudden?
银河对你很好吗？何必拯救它？
What has the galaxy ever done for you? Why would you wanna save it?
因为我是住在里面的乡民啊
Because I'm one of the idiots who lives in it!
彼得，听我说
Peter, listen to me.
不能让宝石落入罗南手中
We cannot allow the Stone to fall into Ronan's hands.
我们必须回你船上
We have to go back to your ship,
把它送给新星军团
and deliver it to Nova.
对，好啦，你说得对
Right, right, okay. I think you're right.
或者交给不会逮捕我们的人
Or we could give it to somebody who's not going to arrest us,
而且他很好心
who's really nice
会给我们一大笔钱
for a whole lot of money.
这样刚好综合你们两个的看法
I think it's a really good balance between both of your points of view.
你真低级
You're despicable.
无耻
Dishonorable.
不可靠
Faithless!
不
- Oh, no. - At last!
终于
我将见到我的敌人，摧毁他
I shall meet my foe and destroy him.
你叫罗南来？
You called Ronan?
奎尔，不要动
Quill! Don't you move, boy!
千万别动
Don't you move! Get out of the way!
让开
控诉者罗南
Ronan the Accuser!
传讯息的人是你？
You are the one who transmitted the message?
你杀了我太太
You killed my Wife.
你杀了我女儿
You killed my daughter!
你挤不进去，等一下，我马上回来
I told you, you can't fit. Now, wait here. I'll be back.
是葛摩菈，她带着灵球逃亡
It is Gamora. She is escaping with the Orb.
不
No!
涅布拉
Nebula,
把灵球拿回来
retrieve the Orb.
宝石在最里面那架飞行舱
The Stone is in the furthest pod.
轰了它
Bring it down!
Ah!
火箭，掩护葛摩菈上米兰号
Rocket, keep them off Gamora until she gets to the Milano.
怎么掩护？这些东西上没武器
How? We've got no weaponry on these things.
这些飞行舱是工业级的
These pods are industrial grade.
几乎坚不可摧
They're nearly indestructible.
它们可抵挡不了死灵炮弹
Not against necroblasts, they're not.
我不是那意思
That's not what I'm saying.
Oh!
让我搭个便车
Let me borrow your ride.
我不记得杀过你家人
I don't recall killing your family.
应该也不会记得杀掉你
I doubt I'll remember killing you, either.
奎尔，我困住了，上不了米兰号
Quill, I'm trapped. I can't make it to the Milano.
我必须出去
I have to head out.
等等，这些飞行舱不该飞出去
Wait! These things aren't meant to go out there.
你真让人失望，姊姊
You are a disappointment, sister.
在所有兄弟姊妹中
Of all our siblings,
我最不讨厌你
I hated you least.
涅布拉，拜托
Nebula, please.
罗南要是拿到这宝石
If Ronan gets this stone
- 他会杀光我们   - 不对
- he'll kill us all. - Not all.
到时候你早就死了
You will already be dead.
罗南，搞定了
Ronan, it is done.
奎尔，别难过
Quill, come on.
她的身体改造能让她多活几分钟
Her body mods should keep her alive a couple more minutes,
但我们无能为力了
but there's nothing we can do for her.
这些飞行舱不该飞出来的
These pods aren't meant to be out here.
我们马上会面临相同处境
In a second, we're gonna be in the same boat.
Aw, damn it.
可恶
奎尔？
Quill?
勇度，勇度
Yondu! Yondu.
我是奎尔，我座标是227K324
This is Quill!
- My coordinates are 227K324. - Quill.
奎尔，你在干嘛？
Quill, what are you doing?
我在知无领域外面
Just outside Knowhere.
你在的话，过来接我
If you're there, come get me.
我全都听你的
I'm all yours.
奎尔，别闹了
Quill, don't be ridiculous.
回你的飞行舱去
Get back into your pod!
舱里挤不了两个人，你会挂掉的
You can't fit two people in there. You're gonna die.
你很快就完蛋了
You'll die in seconds!
Quill.
奎尔？
Quill?
怎么了？
What happened?
我看到你在外面
I saw you out there.
我不知道自己哪来的冲动
I don't know what came over me.
但我不能让你死
But I couldn't let you die.
我发现内心有一种感觉
I found something inside of myself.
一种…
Something
十分英勇的特质
incredibly heroic.
不是我要臭屁
I mean, not to brag,
客观上来说…
but, objectively...
宇宙灵球呢？
Where's the Orb?
它…
It's... Well, they got the Orb.
他们拿走了
什么？
What?
欢迎回家，彼得
Welcome home, Peter.
该死的白痴，全是白痴
Blasted idiot. They're all idiots!
奎尔刚刚自投罗网
Quill just got himself captured.
如果不是你单挑一批大军
None of this ever would have happened if you didn't try to single-handedly
这一切根本不会发生
take on a frickin' army!
你说得对
You're right.
我是笨蛋
I was a fool.
所有的愤怒
All the anger,
所有的怨恨
all the rage,
只为掩饰我失亲的伤痛
was just to cover my loss.
阿娘喂，我老婆小孩死了
Oh, boo-hoo-hoo. "My wife and child are dead."
不好意思我就是这么冷血
Oh, I don't care if it's mean!
谁家不死人啊
Everybody's got dead people.
为了个人目的害死别人
It's no excuse to get everybody else
完全不值得同情
dead along the way!
格鲁特，罗南拿到宝石了
Come on, Groot. Ronan has the Stone.
我们唯一的机会是加快脚步
The only chance we got is to get to the other side of the universe
到宇宙另一端
as fast as we can and maybe,
或许在那个神经病到达前
just maybe, we'll be able to live full lives before that whack-job ever gets there.
我们还能活命
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
救他们？怎么救？
Save them? How?
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
我知道他们是我们仅有的朋友
I know they're the only friends that we ever had,
但他们身边有一批破坏者
but there's an army of Ravagers around them.
我们只有两个人
And there's only two of us!
三个
Three.
Aw!
你们逼得我…
You're making me
霸凌小草…
beat...up
来泄愤
grass!
宇宙灵球在我手上
The Orb is in my possession,
说到做到
as I promised.
拿来给我
Bring it to me.
没错
Yes, that was our agreement.
这是我们的协议
把灵球交给你
Bring you the Orb,
你就替我摧毁柴达
and you will destroy Xandar for me.
但如今我知道它能控制无限宝石
However, now that I know it contains an Infinity Stone,
不知道你还有什么用处
I wonder what use I have for you.
小子
Boy,
你得重新考虑
I would reconsider your current course.
主人
Master! You cannot!
万万不可
萨诺斯是宇宙最具权力者
Thanos is the most powerful being in the universe.
再也不是了
Not anymore.
你叫我"小子"
You call me "boy!"
我会让柴达…
I will unfurl 1,000 years of Kree justice on Xandar,
承受克里的千年折磨
将它烧个精光
and burn it to its core!
然后，萨诺斯
Then, Thanos,
我会来找你
I am coming for you.
摧毁柴达后
After Xandar, you are going to kill my father?
你会杀死我父亲吗？
你敢违抗我？
You dare to oppose me?
你看他害我落得什么下场
You see what he has turned me into.
你杀了他，我帮你摧毁一千个星球
If you kill him, I will help you destroy a thousand planets.
你背叛我？
You betray me?
偷我的钱？
Steal my money?
住手，放开他
Stop it! Leave him alone!
当初我接你过来
When I picked you up as a kid,
这些家伙想吃掉你
these boys wanted to eat you.
他们从未尝过地球人的味道
They ain't never tasted Terran before.
是我救你一命
I saved your life!
别再碎碎念了好吗？天啊
Oh, will you shut up about that? God!
20年来你不断拿这出来讲
Twenty years, you been throwing that in my face,
好像没吃掉我有多了不起
like it's some great thing, not eating me.
正常人根本不会想吃人
Normal people don't even think about eating someone else!
更别说得因此心怀感激
Much less that person having to be grateful for it!
你挟持我
You abducted me, man.
拆散我和家人
You stole me from my home and from my family.
你根本不在乎你的地球
You don't give a damn about your Terra!
你害怕
You're scared
是因为心软
because you're soft in here.
就是这里
Here, right here!
勇度
Yondu!
听我说
Listen to me.
罗南手中拥有无限宝石
Ronan has something called an Infinity Stone.
我知道他有什么
I know what he's got, girl.
那你就知道我们非抢回来不可
Then you know we must get it back!
他会用来摧毁柴达
He's gonna use it to wipe out Xandar.
我们得警告他们，数十亿人将死去
We have to warn them. Billions of people will perish.
她一直灌输你这观念吗，小子？
Is that what she's been filling your head with, boy?
多愁善感？
Sentiment?
你都被洗脑了
Eating away your brain like maggots!
到此为止
That's it.
不
No!
抱歉，小子
Sorry, boy.
老大得让手下明白背叛的下场
But a captain's gotta teach his men what happens to those what cross him.
杀鸡儆猴
Captain's gotta teach stuff!
如果你现在杀了我
If you kill me now,
就是跟金银财宝过不去
you are saying goodbye to the biggest score you have ever seen.
那个宝石吗？
The Stone?
希望你有比那更棒的东西
I hope you got something better than that.
因为没人能偷走罗南的东西
Because ain't nobody stealing from Ronan.
我们有优势
We got a ringer.
是吗？
Is that right?
她对罗南了若指掌
She knows everything there is to know about Ronan.
他的太空船
His ships,
他的军队
his army.
他根本不堪一击
He's vulnerable.
怎么样，勇度？
Hey, what do you say, Yondu, huh?
你我像过去一样，携手合作
Me and you, taking down a mark side-by-side, like the old days.
放了他
Let him go!
你一向很有guts，小子
You always did have a scrote, boy!
所以当初我才把你留在身边
That's why I kept you on as a young'un.
队长，那一击没造成损害
Captain, the shot was non-damaging.
各位白痴注意
Attention, idiots.
船顶那个疯子拿着强子冲锋枪
The lunatic on top of this craft is holding a Hadron Enforcer.
那是本大爷亲自设计的武器
It's a weapon of my own design.
搞什么？
What the hell?
如果不马上交出我们的同伴
If you don't hand over our companions now,
他会把你们的船轰出一个洞
he's gonna tear your ship a new one.
新鲜出炉的大洞
A very big new one!
- 我不相信   - 我数到五
- I ain't buyin' it. - I'm giving you to the count of five.
- 五，四，三   - 不，等一下
- 5, 4, 3... - No! Wait, hold on!
火箭，是我，老天
Rocket, it's me, for God sakes!
我们搞定了，我们没事
We figured it out! We're fine!
奎尔，怎么回事？
Oh, hey, Quill. What's going on?
这样叫搞定了？
You call that "figured it out"?
我们要报复痛宰我们的那些家伙
We're gonna rob the guys who just beat us senseless.
你还有脸讲？
Oh, you want to talk about senseless?
你救我们的方法，竟是炸死我们
How about trying to save us by blowing us up?
他们不放走你们，我们才会炸
We were only gonna blow you up if they didn't turn you over!
你只给他们五秒钟
And how on earth were they gonna turn us over
他们要怎么放走我们？
when you only gave them a count of five?
我们哪有时间考虑
We didn't have time to work out the minutiae
这种枝微末节
of the plan.
好心给雷亲
This is what we get for acting altruistically.
我是格鲁特
- I am Groot. - They are ungrateful.
他们真不知感激
现在重要的是
What's important now
让破坏者大军
is we get the Ravagers' army
帮我们拯救柴达
to help us save Xandar.
好让勇度把宝石卖给更危险的人？
So we can give the Stone to Yondu
who's just gonna sell to somebody even worse?
这部分晚点再说
We'll figure that part out later.
我们必须阻止罗南
We have to stop Ronan.
怎么做？
How?
我有个计划
I have a plan.
你有计划？
You've got a plan?
对
Yes.
首先，你学我说你有计划
First of all, you're copying me from
- when I said I had a plan. - No, I'm not.
哪有
很多人这么说，跟吃饭一样
People say that all the time. It's not that unique of a thing to say.
第二，我根本不信你有计划
Secondly, I don't even believe you have a plan.
我有…一部分的计划
I have part of a plan!
你有几趴的计划？
What percentage of a plan do you have?
你干了蠢事，没你说话的份
You don't get to ask questions
after the nonsense you pulled on Knowhere.
我刚刚救了奎尔
I just saved Quill.
我们已经认定
We've already established
摧毁我的船不算救我
that you destroying the ship that I'm on is not saving me.
- 何时认定的？   - 三秒前
- When did we establish it? - Like three seconds ago!
我没听到，我在想别的事
I wasn't listening. I was thinking of something else.
她说得对，你无权发言
She's right. You don't get an opinion.
有几趴？
What percentage?
不知道，12趴
I don't know. Twelve percent.
12趴？
Twelve percent?
你假笑
That's a fake laugh.
- 是真的   - 假到不行
- It's real! - Totally fake.
这是我一生最真实诚恳的狂笑
That is the most real, authentic, hysterical laugh of my entire life
那根本不算计划
because that is not a plan.
连概念都算不上
It's barely a concept.
你挺他们？
You're taking their side?
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
怎样，比11趴好吗？
So what, it's better than 11%?
那到底有什么关系？
What the hell does that have to do with anything?
谢谢你，格鲁特
Thank you, Groot. Thank you.
谢谢
看吧？只有格鲁特搞得清楚状况
See? Groot's the only one of you who has a clue.
伙伴们
Guys.
别这样
Come on.
勇度马上就来了
Yondu is gonna be here in two seconds.
他希望听到我们的伟大计划
He expects to hear this big plan of ours.
我需要你们帮忙
I need your help.
我看着大家
I look around at us.
知道我看到什么吗？
You know what I see?
一群鲁蛇
Losers.
就像
I mean, like,
失去灵魂的人
folks who have lost stuff.
我们全都失去了很多
And we have. Man, we have. All of us.
失去家园
Our homes,
家人
our families,
正常生活
normal lives.
人生通常苦多于乐，但今天不同
And, usually, life takes more than it gives. But not today.
今天人生给了我们一样东西
Today, it's given us something.
它给我们机会
It has given us a chance.
什么机会？
To do what?
认真面对
To give a shit.
至少这么一次
For once.
不逃避
Not run away.
我不会袖手旁观
I, for one, am not gonna stand by and watch
看着罗南杀害几十亿条性命
as Ronan wipes out billions of innocent lives.
奎尔，要阻止罗南
But, Quill, stopping Ronan,
是不可能的任务
it's impossible.
你是要我们去送死
You're asking us to die.
我猜是吧
Yeah, I guess I am.
奎尔
Quill.
我一辈子都被敌人围绕
I have lived most my life surrounded by my enemies.
死在朋友身边是我的荣幸
I will be grateful to die among my friends.
你令人尊敬，奎尔
You are an honorable man, Quill.
我愿意与你并肩作战
I will fight beside you.
到最后
And in the end,
我会再见到太太和女儿
I will see my wife and daughter again.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
管他的
Oh, what the hell. I don't got that long a lifespan, anyway.
反正大爷我也活不了那么久
我挺身而出，高兴了吧？
Now I'm standing. Y'all happy?
我们都挺身而出了
We're all standing up now.
一群天兵围成一圈
Bunch of jackasses, standing in a circle.
宝石会与有机物发生反应
The Stone reacts to anything organic.
目标越大，力量越强
The bigger the target, the bigger the power surge.
罗南只要让宝石碰触星球表面
All Ronan's got to do is touch the Stone to the planet's surface and zap.
所有动植物
All plants, animals,
- 新星军团   - 万物皆死
- Nova Corps. - Everything will die.
所以罗南不能登陆
So Ronan does not make the surface.
火箭率领队伍在暗星号的右舷
PETER: Rocket will lead a team to blow a hole
炸出一个洞
in the Dark Aster's starboard hull.
然后我们太空船和勇度会进入
Then, our craft and Yondu's will enter.
里面不是有…
Won't there be hundreds of Sakaaran soldiers inside?
几百名萨卡士兵吗？
萨卡人跟纸糊的一样
I think of Sakaaran as paper people.
他们一旦知道我们上船
Once they know we're on board,
罗南就会躲到安全门后面
Ronan will isolate himself behind impenetrable security doors on deck.
我切断电源就能打开
Which I can disable by dismantling the power source.
我们降落在飞行甲板上
We'll make it to the flight deck,
我用强子冲锋枪杀死罗南
and I'll use the Hadron Enforcer to kill Ronan.
罗南一死，就能夺回宝石
Once Ronan is dead, we will retrieve the Stone.
用这些装置控制它，只要一碰它
Use these devices to contain it.
If you touch it,
你就会没命
it will kill you.
我会跟逮捕我们的新星军官联络
I'll contact one of the Nova officers
who arrested us.
希望他们相信我们是去帮忙的
Hopefully, they'll believe we're there to help.
（彼得奎尔来电）
完成计划还需要一样东西
There's one more thing we need to complete the plan.
那家伙的眼睛
That guy's eye.
不
No! No, we don't. No, we don't need
不，我们不需要
那位的眼睛
that guy's eye.
我真的想要，对我很重要
No, seriously, I need it! It's important to me.
发现罗南的舰队
Ronan's fleet has been spotted,
and will arrive in T-minus
15分钟后抵达
fifteen minutes.
记住，小子
Remember, boy.
到了最后
At the end of all this,
宝石归我
I get the Stone.
敢呼拢我，你们都别想活
You cross me, we kill you all.
杀他们片甲不留
Let's go get 'em, boys!
这计划很糟糕
This is a terrible plan.
是你说要死在朋友身边的
Hey, you're the one who said you wanted to die among friends.
总司令
Nova Prime.
我收到一名破坏者
I received a transmission
传来的讯息
from one of the Ravagers.
他说罗南手上握有无限宝石
He says Ronan's in possession of something called an Infinity Stone
正往柴达星前进
and he's headed toward Xandar.
我的老天
Good God.
这是诡计，他是罪犯
It's a trick. He's a criminal.
他有说我们为何该相信他吗？
Did he say why we should believe him?
他说他们一伙刚越狱
He said his crew just escaped from prison
我们不必冒险到柴达协助
so he'd have no other reason to risk coming to Xandar to help.
他说他是一个…
He says that he's an
猪头
"a-hole."
但不是…
But he's not,
我引用他的话
and I'm quoting him, here,
"正港的贱货"
"100% a dick."
你相信他吗？
Do you believe him?
我不知道是否有人是正港贱货
I don't know that I believe anyone is 100% a dick, ma'am.
你相信他是来帮忙的吗？
I mean, do you believe that he is here to help?
相信
Yeah.
有舰队接近
A fleet approaches.
好像是破坏者
They appear to be Ravagers.
开火
Fire!
跟着下去
Cover it down.
往下飞
Submerge!
火箭，快点
Rocket, hurry!
全体飞行员，下降
All pilots, dive!
他们在我们下方
They're beneath us!
本市撤离
Evacuate the city.
我们优先让民众远离战争
Our priority is to get our people away from the battle.
全速前进
Forward thrust, now!
放马过来
Come on!
奎尔，勇度，快点
Quill! Yondu! Now!
完了
Aw, hell!
我要坠毁了，奎尔
I'm going down, Quill!
别再耍我了，小子
No more games with me, boy!
战争结束后
I'll see you
我再跟你见面
at the end of this!
他们人太多了，火箭
There are too many of them, Rocket!
我们撑不下去的
We'll never make it up there!
彼得奎尔
Peter Quill.
我是新星军团的丹纳萨尔
This is Denarian Saal of the Nova Corps.
我提议不能信任你
For the record, I advised against trusting you here.
他们收到我的讯息了
They got my "dick" message!
证明我错了
Prove me wrong.
帅
Yes!
我们就像凯文贝肯
We're just like Kevin Bacon.
右舷船尾受损
The starboard kern has been breached!
有人攻上来了
We have been boarded.
继续前进
Continue our approach.
但新星军团发动攻势了
But the Nova Corps have engaged.
登陆之后这些都无所谓
None of that will matter once we reach the surface.
封锁安全门
Seal security doors!
快点
Now!
别挡路
Get out of my way!
天啊
Oh, man.
新星飞行员，形成屏障队形
All Nova pilots, interlock and form a blockade.
千万别让暗星号登陆
The Dark Aster must not reach the ground.
就位
Locked in!
Locked in.
就位
We're locked in.
我几乎看不见
I can barely see.
你什么时候学的？
When did you learn to do that?
答案一定是
Pretty sure the answer is
我是格鲁特
"I am Groot."
飞行甲板往这边300公尺
The flight deck is 300 meters this way.
感谢大家在我犯错后还接纳我
I want you all to know that I am grateful for your acceptance after my blunders.
很高兴再一次交到…
It is pleasing to once again have
朋友
friends.
奎尔，你是我朋友
You, Quill, are my friend.
谢谢
Thanks.
这棵蠢树是我朋友
- This dumb tree, he is my friend. - Mmm.
还有这个绿脸妹也是
And this green whore, she, too...
唛搁讲了
Oh, you must stop!
葛摩菈
Gamora, look at what you have done.
看看你干的好事
你一向意志薄弱
You have always been weak.
脑残的叛徒
You stupid, traitorous...
不准这样跟我朋友说话
Nobody talks to my friends like that.
前往飞行甲板
Head to the flight deck.
我去切断安全门的电力
I'll shut down the power to the security doors.
勇度
Yondu Udonta.
命令你的手下背叛新星军团
Order your men to turn on the Nova Corps.
破坏者，闹够了没，受死吧
Enough nonsense, Ravager!
Time to die...
涅布拉，求求你
Nebula, please.
够了，死灵号飞行员
Enough of this. Necrocraft pilots,
开始全力进攻
enact immolation initiative.
他们开始俯冲轰炸了
They're dive-bombing the city!
丹纳萨尔，应该散开吗？
Denarian Saal, should we break formation?
不，维持队形
No! Hold your positions.
让罗南待在上面，萨尔
Keep Ronan up there, Saal.
我们会解决下面这些人
We'll take care of the people down here.
我竟然听一只仓鼠的命令
I can't believe I'm taking orders from a hamster.
星爵
Star-Lord.
你终于上道了！
Finally.
Ah!
你这个小偷
You thief!
你们休想逮到罗南
You will never make it to Ronan.
火力全开，别让他们登陆
Everybody shoot them before they hit the ground.
来吧
Come on!
手指放在脖子上代表死亡
Finger to the throat means death.
比喻
Metaphor.
差不多
Yeah, sorta.
不
Oh, no.
柴达
Xandar!
你们罪该万死
You stand accused.
可悲的和平协定
Your wretched peace treaty will not
也救不了你们
save you now.
它只会送你们上西天
It is the tinder on which you burn.
火箭
Rocket!
撑一下，萨尔
Hold on, Saal, just...
奎尔，动作快
Quill, you gotta hurry.
市民撤离了，但我们兵败如山倒
The city's been evacuated,
but we're getting our asses kicked down here.
葛摩菈还没把门打开
Gamora hasn't opened the door!
涅布拉
Nebula!
妹妹，帮我们对抗罗南
Sister, help us fight Ronan.
你明知他疯了
You know he's crazy.
我知道你们两个都疯了
I know you're both crazy.
不
No!
怎么…
- What the...? - Ah!
出去
Get out!
你成功了
You did it!
我弄错了
I was mistaken.
我记得你家人
I do remember your family.
他们的惨叫声
Their screams were
痛苦至极，我…
pitiful. I...
不，格鲁特
No, Groot!
不可以
You can't.
你会没命的
You'll die.
为什么要这么做？
Why are you doing this?
为什么？
Why?
我们是格鲁特
We
are
Groot.
我还叫他北七
I called him an idiot.
你杀死了格鲁特
You killed Groot!
看
Behold!
就靠这些废柴保护你们的银河吗
Your guardians of the galaxy.
他们做了什么？
What fruit have they wrought?
只有让我父亲和祖父
Only that my father and his father
终于能够复仇
shall finally know vengeance.
柴达人
People of Xandar,
时候到了
the time has come
你们应该欢欣鼓舞
to rejoice and renounce
抛弃你们卑劣的神
Your paltry gods!
你们即将获救
Your salvation is at hand.
听听这些歌词
Listen to these words.
跳起来
Now bring it down hard!
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
来尬舞啊，我和你
Dance-off, bro. Me and you.
葛摩菈
Gamora.
动作太小，换我
Subtle. Take it back.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
转移你注意力，大猪头
I'm distracting you, you big turd blossom.
不
No!
彼得，拉我的手
Peter! Take my hand!
拉着我的手，彼得
Take my hand, Peter.
妈
Mom.
拉着我的手
Take my hand!
你们只是凡人
You're mortal!
怎么可能？
How?
你自己说的，笨蛋
You said it yourself, bitch.
这银河，是我们在罩的！
We're the Guardians of the Galaxy.
唉呀呀
Well, Well, Well.
好精彩的灯光秀
Quite the light show.
真甜蜜
Ain't this sweet.
不过开始嘿咻之前
But you got some business to attend to
你还有事要做
before all the nookie-nookie starts.
彼得，不可以
Peter, you can't. Peter.
你得重新考虑，勇度
You gotta reconsider this, Yondu.
我不知道你会卖谁，但宇宙要存续
I don't know who you're selling this to,
but the only way the universe can survive
你非把它交给新星军团不可
is if you give it to the Nova Corps.
虽然
I may be as pretty as an angel,
我的外表美如天使
但可没他们那么善良
but I sure as hell ain't one.
拿过来，小子
Hand it over, son.
勇度
Yondu.
不能打开那颗球，你知道吧？
Do not open that Orb. You know that, right?
你见识过它的威力
You've seen what it does to people.
结果奎尔挺可靠的
Yeah, Quill turned out okay.
我们没把他送到他爸那边
It's probably good we didn't deliver him to his dad
应该是好事
like we was hired to do.
对，那家伙是混帐
Yeah, that guy was a jackass.
他若发现我把灵球调包
He is gonna be so pissed when he realizes I switched out the Orb on him.
肯定很火大
他本来会杀了你，彼得
我知道
Oh, I know.
但他是我唯一的家人
But he was about the only family I had.
不
No.
不只有他
He wasn't.
你们怎么会知道？
Why would you even know this?
我们逮捕你时发现你神经系统异常
When we arrested you, we noticed an anomaly in your nervous system,
所以做了检查
so we had it checked out.
我不是地球人？
I'm not Terran?
你是半个地球人
You are half Terran.
你母亲是地球人，你父亲…
Your mother was of Earth. Your father, well,
他是我们从未见过的古老物种
he's something very ancient we've never seen here before.
那可能就是
That could be why you were able
你可以握着灵球这么久的原因
to hold the Stone for as long as you did.
你的朋友抵达了
Your friends have arrived.
我们想代表新星军团
On behalf of the Nova Corps,
深深感谢各位
we'd like to express our profound gratitude
协助拯救柴达
for your help in saving Xandar.
请你们跟丹纳戴走
If you will follow Denarian Dey,
他带你们去看一样东西
he has something to show you.
谢谢总司令
Thank you, Nova Prime.
知道你为他们报仇
Your wife and child shall rest well knowing that you have avenged them.
你太太和孩子能安息了
没错
Yes.
当然，罗南只是傀儡
Of course, Ronan was only a puppet.
我要杀的其实是萨诺斯
It's really Thanos I need to kill.
我们尽量维持它的原貌
We tried to keep it as close to the original as possible.
尽全力抢救了
We salvaged as much as we could.
哇塞
Wow.
I...
谢谢
Thank you.
我有家人
I have a family.
他们多亏你们才活着
They're alive because of you.
你们的前科纪录也都撤销了
Your criminal records have also been expunged.
但我得警告你们未来别再犯法
However, I have to warn you against breaking any laws in the future.
我有问题
Question.
我想拿的东西如果是别人的呢？
What if I see something that I want to take,
and it belongs to someone else?
你会被逮捕
You will be arrested.
如果我比对方更想要它呢？
But what if I want it more than the person who has it?
- 还是违法   - 没道理
- It's still illegal. - That doesn't follow.
我比较想要，你懂吗？
No, I want it more, sir. Do you understand?
你们笑什么？
What are you laughing at?
我不能和这位先生讨论一下吗？
Why? I can't have a discussion with this gentleman?
如果有人做了讨厌的事
What if someone does something irksome
我想折断他的脊椎呢？
and I decide to remove his spine?
That's...
那是谋杀
That's actually murder.
最恶劣的罪行之一
It's one of the worst crimes of all.
所以还是犯法
So... also illegal.
Hmm.
他们会很规矩的
They'll be fine, Dey.
我会紧盯着他们
I'm gonna keep an eye on 'em.
凭你？
You?
对，就是我
Yeah. Me.
（给彼得）
彼得
Peter,
我知道这几个月你很难受
I know these last few months have been hard for you.
但我要去一个更美好的地方
But I'm going to a better place.
我会好好的
And I will be okay.
我也会永远在你身边
And I will always be with you.
你是我的生命之光
You are the light of my life.
我的宝贝儿子
My precious son.
我的小星爵
My little Star-Lord.
爱你的妈妈
Love, Mom.
（劲爆舞曲大帝国第二集）
接下来该做什么？好事？
So, what should we do next?
Something good?
坏事？
Something bad?
好坏参半？
A bit of both?
我们追随你，星爵
We'll follow your lead, Star-Lord.
那就好坏全包了
Bit of both.
（星际异攻队的旅程还没结束）
你干嘛让它舔你？
What do you let it lick you like that for?
好恶
Gross.
Yeah!
喉咙好像烧起来了
But it burns going down.